ivcc.edu 2003-02-28

# IVCC > Interim Designation of Agent to Receive Notification of Claimed Infringement

## IVCC Privacy Statement

### General Statement of Privacy

Illinois Valley Community College (IVCC) is committed to protecting your privacy. This statement explains how IVCC uses information that is collected from you when you give information to us through our Web sites.

### Collecting and Controlling Your Personal Information

IVCC will tell you when it collects information from you. This information is usually sent by you on a volunteer basis, usually through our online application, contact us form, or via e-mail.

### Use of Personal Information

This information is collected to provide better customer service, for research purposes, to reply to inquiries and to meet Federal and State reporting requirements.

### Disclosure of information to outside parties

IVCC will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  1. Conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on IVCC or the its Web sites.
  2. Protect and defend the rights or property of IVCC or its Web sites.
  3. Act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users its Web sites, the public or the general safety of its employees.

### Management of Your Personal Information

E-mail received is distributed to the appropriate individual.

Information is put into our administrative software.

### Access to Your Personal Information

Individuals who apply to the college should review our [FERPA page](http://www.ivcc.edu/admissions/ferpa.html) for more information.

  1. IVCC does not sell nor distribute your information to advertisers.
  2. Library records are considered confidential information.

### Security of your Personal Information

Please note that information will be submitted via **non** -secure e-mail.  Please do not send your Social Security Number or other information that you would not want someone else to know.  Individuals under the age of 13 should not use this form.

### Protection of Children’s Personal Information

Individuals under the age of 13 must get parental consent to send personal information through our Web site or via e-mail.  For more information on the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 please visit the [Federal Trade Commission](http://www.ftc.gov/ogc/coppa1.htm) Web site.

The term "personal information" means individually identifiable information about an individual collected online, including— 

(A) a first and last name;

(B) a home or other physical address including street name and name of a city or town;

(C) an e-mail address;

(D) a telephone number;

(E) a Social Security number;

(F) any other identifier that the Commission determines permits the physical or online contacting of a specific individual; or

(G) information concerning the child or the parents of that child that the website collects online from the child and combines with an identifier described in this paragraph.

### Changes to this Statement

IVCC reserves the right to make changes to this statement when necessary. If the college does, the notice of update will be placed on the [home page](http://www.ivcc.edu/) of our Web site.

### Contact Information

IVCC welcomes any comments that you might have on this statement. Please send e-mail to [webmaster@ivcc.edu](mailto:webmaster@ivcc.edu) or postal correspondence to:

Illinois Valley Community College  
Privacy Statement: Learning Technologies  
815 North Orlando Smith Ave.  
Oglesby, IL 61348

The IVCC Privacy Statement was originally developed by the IVCC Technology Team in 2002.
## IVCC Privacy Statement

### General Statement of Privacy

Illinois Valley Community College (IVCC) is committed to protecting your privacy. This statement explains how IVCC uses information that is collected from you when you give information to us through our Web sites.

### Collecting and Controlling Your Personal Information

IVCC will tell you when it collects information from you. This information is usually sent by you on a volunteer basis, usually through our online application, contact us form, or via e-mail.

### Use of Personal Information

This information is collected to provide better customer service, for research purposes, to reply to inquiries and to meet Federal and State reporting requirements.

### Disclosure of information to outside parties

IVCC will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  1. Conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on IVCC or the its Web sites.
  2. Protect and defend the rights or property of IVCC or its Web sites.
  3. Act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users its Web sites, the public or the general safety of its employees.

### Management of Your Personal Information

E-mail received is distributed to the appropriate individual.

Information is put into our administrative software.

### Access to Your Personal Information

Individuals who apply to the college should review our [FERPA page](http://www.ivcc.edu/admissions/ferpa.html) for more information.

  1. IVCC does not sell nor distribute your information to advertisers.
  2. Library records are considered confidential information.

### Security of your Personal Information

Please note that information will be submitted via **non** -secure e-mail.  Please do not send your Social Security Number or other information that you would not want someone else to know.  Individuals under the age of 13 should not use this form.

### Protection of Children’s Personal Information

Individuals under the age of 13 must get parental consent to send personal information through our Web site or via e-mail.  For more information on the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 please visit the [Federal Trade Commission](http://www.ftc.gov/ogc/coppa1.htm) Web site.

The term "personal information" means individually identifiable information about an individual collected online, including— 

(A) a first and last name;

(B) a home or other physical address including street name and name of a city or town;

(C) an e-mail address;

(D) a telephone number;

(E) a Social Security number;

(F) any other identifier that the Commission determines permits the physical or online contacting of a specific individual; or

(G) information concerning the child or the parents of that child that the website collects online from the child and combines with an identifier described in this paragraph.

### Changes to this Statement

IVCC reserves the right to make changes to this statement when necessary. If the college does, the notice of update will be placed on the [home page](http://www.ivcc.edu/) of our Web site.

### Contact Information

IVCC welcomes any comments that you might have on this statement. Please send e-mail to [webmaster@ivcc.edu](mailto:webmaster@ivcc.edu) or postal correspondence to:

Illinois Valley Community College  
Privacy Statement: Learning Technologies  
815 North Orlando Smith Ave.  
Oglesby, IL 61348

The IVCC Privacy Statement was originally developed by the IVCC Technology Team in 2002.
